Mohammed Abdul Moyeed

Portfolio: https://moyeed.github.io/

E-Mail: abdulmoyeedm96@gmail.com Mobile: +1 (309) 868-7433 LinkedIn: http://www.linkedin.com/in/abdul-moyeed-mohammed

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Individual with strong Analytical and critical thinking abilities with more than **3 years of software engineering experience** demonstrated in successfully managing and executing **software development projects** with strong understanding in computer Science concepts. **Passionate for learning** new technologies and contributing towards developing more **challenging software projects**. Currently pursuing master's in computer science from Northern Illinois University.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Programming/Scripting Languages: Nodejs-JavaScript (2 years), Python(1 year) and Java (0.5 years)

Cloud Platforms: Amazon Web Services (LEX, lambda, elastic search, elastic cache, step functions, SQS, SNS, Cloud

formation, Comprehend, Connect, Dynamo DB, etc.), Twilio.

Chat Bot Environments: Amazon Lex, Google Dialog flow, Infosys NIA.

Other: Agile, GitHub, Rest API's, Requirement Gathering, Research, Debugging, Testing, Code review.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Northern Illinois University

Graduate Research Assistant

Dekalb, IL, USA

January 2021 – Present

- Develop **Object-Oriented code with Python** to add new features or improve the existing features of the research related to Trajectory Visualization.
- Analyzing and improving the current Algorithms to get better code Efficiency.
- Brainstorming Ideas to achieve and improve research questions related to project.

Infosys Limited. Hyderabad, India

Senior Systems Engineer

July 2020 - January 2021

- Developed a Virtual Assistant for handling user queries from basic FAQ to various topics required using AWS services like Amazon Lex as chatbot platform, Amazon Lambda, API Gateway, Dynamo DB as NOSQL database, elastic Cache, Elastic search, Comprehend, Connect, SQS, SNS, and step functions.
- Integrated the Virtual Assistant over **Teams, SMS, Voice and Web** modalities Using Microsoft Azure, Twilio, and Rest API's.
- Adding new features and fixing bugs in the Assistant every Sprint based on Agile process.
- This Assistant has reduced the number of calls answered by live agents by **25%** during the launch and increased as the project moved on to **40%**.

Systems Engineer

October 2018 – July 2020

- Developed a Web based Chatbot with Google Dialog flow using JavaScript and Rest API Integration.
- Integrated chatbot with Skype and Service Now to realize clients' requirements.
- Developed various Proof of Concepts to gain clients confidence.

Systems Engineer Trainee

June 2018 - October 2018

- Trained and certified with Infosys on object-oriented programming with Python and Java, core Java with spring,
 DBMS, Data Structures, Angular, TypeScript, JavaScript, REST API's.
- Completed Infosys training with 85%.
- worked with a team on an E commerce website development for about a month.

EDUCATION

Northern Illinois University

Dekalb, IL, USA

Master of Science, Computer Science (GPA: 3.9 – till second semester)

Expected: Aug 2022

Hyderabad, India

Muffakham Jah College of Engineering and Technology

May 2018

Bachelor of Engineering, Electronics and Communication Engineering.

ACHEIVEMENTS

• Received two Insta Awards as an appreciation for commitment and flexibility towards client project which helped us gain client confidence.